good morning let's do lion stance
turn off your phone please
rushon
powder okay
today let's go through the whole thing
alright which means we'll go up and
we'll come back down okay and we want to
our Oh twaddle dawdle we'll go through
it without much explanation
clear your throat blow your nose
you
so relax your shoulders and relax your
fingers
try to keep your forehead relaxed
I like to find the center point with my
spine so go left and right and find the
center and then go back and forward
and I think you'll find when you hit a
sweet spot it feels like your spine is
weight weightless and for me that's a
little farther back than normal
same with your head your head is
actually pretty heavy and you have to
balance it on the spine probably have to
move it back a little bit
relax your fingers
pull in your stomach just a little bit
every time you exhale you can tighten
your stomach a little bit not crazy but
just a little bit it helps keep your
lower spine straight I find when the
weather is cold which it's a little cold
here this morning I put my I can put my
hands in my lap and closeness of my arms
to my body makes me warmer and then if
the weather's hot I I put my arms out
and I put my hands on my thighs
you might find that your back stays more
straight
if you move your hands back on your
thighs
and then you can come to a noise in the
room we have
fan noise and that's a desirable
and follow that for ten breaths
you
and then come to the first program level
your heartbeat
you
then go into the heartbeat
and observed the heartbeat from a
without any emotional involvement with
you
and imagine a greenish sugar
and put your mind inside drop the heart
you
then imagine a vast lake drop a pebble
in the middle and see a ripple go each
way inside your mind
you
come back to the center of your mind
turn on a light of awareness and watch
this clear line expand infinitely
you
and simply shut off the mind and block
any thoughts that come
you
and now turn off the mine but
thoughts to flow through if they want to
don't resist
you
and bring one of your teachers in your
knife
to sit in front of you
you
and then think of one of the things
about them one of the qualities you
admire
you
now come to the center of your mind
and see
silver
seeds eggs
you
shining
and then stall day one of them cracks
open
out of it comes
image made of light of this quality you
enjoy in your teacher and it passes to
the outside in front of you
and settles on the teacher and you
realize that what you see in your
teacher has been coming from you all
this time
you
and I must have planted the seeds partly
at least partly in a past life and go on
an imaginary journey
we create
past life and use all the fleeting
images that come to your mind any
experience you've had in the last few
days you can use that material
to make a movie of your past life so be
creative feel unrestrained it could have
been any world could have been in
anybody that you were wearing you could
have been any occupation but you are
showing this good quality to other
people
you
and then come back to the image of your
teacher and respectfully ask them to
move to the side
now imagine a teacher who looked the
same in front of you but this one is not
coming from you
it's just accidental
they have been created accidentally by
accidental forces in the world outer
world and you have met them by accident
and there's no shared destiny with them
just random and try to get a sense of
how wrong that feels
you
then cancel that impossible random
teacher and try to get a sense of the
space that's left behind in front of you
when you cancel them when you deny that
they exist then there's a kind of space
or availability white movie screen in
front of you left behind by their
absence
this is emptiness try to put your mind
into that space try to hold it in the
mind for as long as you can next
experiment with ways of relating to this
space it's not a physical space it's the
absence of a teacher who was impossible
try to leave that other parts of the
world and your mind and try to enter
this space and just think on it
you
and you can ask your teacher to come
back in front of you the one who's
coming from you and I'd like to imagine
that day I'd like to picture the
emptiness of the Occidental picture a
Occidental teacher is still at the core
of the real teacher it's it's the space
in which they can exist
you
and we'll do the second part of the lion
stance will come down the eight levels
go back to turning off to mine and
allowing surrendering to any
distractions that come
you
in seventh level come down to turning
off the mine but resisting random
thoughts feelings
you
then bring the clear light the great
sphere clear line start bringing it back
from the edges of the universe back
towards you towards the center of your
mind
you
bring the ripples of the leg back
go back into the grain of sugar
you
and come back to the heart beating in a
vacuum distance from you
you
and back inside the heart beating
and then back into yourself watching the
heart beating in your chest
you
in follow three long exhales imagine
each exhale is a golden colored line and
with that line spreading out to this
place people in this place people in
this country people in this world and
the breath the golden light is touching
them and sharing with them this
beautiful knowledge that the world is
coming from my seeds and I can make a
perfect one three long exhales
you
you can gently open your eyes any
questions any microphone I'm having a
hard time with level seven and eight
Chiana I don't how can I turn off my
mind any sense to me okay
venerable Paula said she's having
trouble with seven and eight which is
called the 7s to young me
ADIS do she made you seem a min and
seven is a famous argument over level
seven
because actually you cannot shut off
your mind it's not possible and you're
supposed to try and you you'll find
something that feels like shutting off
you mind as if someone had conked you
out or you're in a deep sleep but you
shouldn't feel bad because actually you
cannot shut off human and there was a
big argument about it
for many centuries and some Buddhist
teachers were teaching it as a path to
Nirvana
and they were teaching it as seeing
emptiness which it's not related at all
right there's no connection at all but
they misunderstood the meaning of
emptiness and they thought you could
turn off the mind but it's not it's
actually not possible if you're watching
the mind turned off then the mind is on
and the harder you try to turn it off
the more you think so you can imagine
that the mind is turned on and the point
is to get extremely quiet and you know
and I think it's interesting probably
your graduate students will write books
about you know then why do you go to
level 8 and why do you let the mind
think of some things and then try to
pretend they're not there and there must
be some big meaning between 7 and 8 also
like to go from blocking the thoughts
which takes more effort and it's more
noisy to allowing thoughts to float
through your mind okay so those two are
very attractive when I was in Europe
recently teaching this in Romania
Romanians are very romantic
probably romantic comes from Romania now
but they were like oh gosh not now you
really taught us meditation you know and
I was like no these are the worst - you
know these are the two famous mistakes
that people make in history and they
think it's emptiness and they think it's
gonna help them the Karma of stopping
and getting off at the seventh floor or
the eighth floor the Karma is very
famous the seed you plant by stopping at
7 or 8 is that you become forgetful and
you lose your keys and you lose your
cell phone
you can't remember your social security
number and things like that
it's a strange car man you don't want
that car man you don't want to stop
there okay very famous karma and a very
famous mistake so don't be too attracted
to it and you can't do it actually but
try other question yeah
thank you for K for a teaching job I
have a big confusion because sometimes
sometimes just shut down my mind
sometimes I open the lion I don't know
every time in different level I will
feel that it's a little bit seems that I
fall asleep yeah but it's different
because and Tong land or something I
will totally fall asleep then it will be
several hours later that I will come
back but every time I do the lion dance
no matter here or listening the record I
will I will say I will get to I will
hear that please get back to your mind
or something like that I I can so I can
go back every time so I'm I'm not sure
that but I am really sleeping or I am
into some level that I am otherwise I am
following your instruction or something
okay when I do number 7 I always think
of jetsam kapa there's a famous story
that he was doing level 7 in the tempo
with a you know like 500 other month and
then he did shut off he mean it came
close to shutting off his mine and then
they rang the bell and everybody else
left and he stayed there because he
couldn't hear anything because his mind
was shut off and then that night like 10
hours later somebody found him in the
temple he's still sitting there with his
mind they're like wake up it's over and
sometimes I worry about that like I'm
I'm very worried that I'll miss
breakfast so yeah there must be some
part of your mind
that is still listening right to their
recording because when I say come back
you come back so yeah I think there are
many levels of the mind and we are going
quieter each time and I don't think
you're completely asleep I don't think
you're asleep I think you're just mind
is going down to a quiet level and
that's fine that's part of the exercise
one day I fell asleep completely and hit
my head on the wall and that's a
different thing that that means you
didn't have enough sleep the night
before so you're just kind of moving to
a lower state of consciousness quiet
quieter place and that's fine and if you
do it really well maybe we'll find you
and your cabin next week still sitting
so that's fine don't worry about it it
sounds good to me okay yeah you're not
asleep there's a weird thing about four
kinds of consciousness waking
consciousness Beachley dream sleep like
that probably you're going down to dream
sleep something like that
you
Thank You Kasia thanks for coming by the
way will is one of the first students
here and he did all the tile on all the
windows many years ago
thank you for that
[Applause]
thank you
so my question level 9 we cancel out the
the booboo teacher and for me there's a
boo boo me there and the eggs are boo
boos and and I want to see where and so
as I go down where does all that come
from where does that arise from yeah
good so well will what will is saying is
that not only do I normally have a
feeling that these things around me are
not coming from me but that also applies
to me my own awareness of myself I I
don't have a full appreciation that my
own thoughts are coming from seeds and
the person meditating is coming from
seeds and the meditation is coming from
seeds and you can go there if you want
that's okay
that's called the three spheres and you
can if you have time you can appreciate
that the person meditating is also
coming from seeds and you can I think
it's very fruitful to
picture that the meditation itself is
coming from seeds and obviously the
object is the the llama is coming from
seeds but there is a practice where you
examine how all three are coming from
seeds and you can cancel all of three
who are not coming from seeds and that's
a beautiful meditation and that's a good
place to go
they say it's particularly useful when
you're angry at somebody or you're upset
at somebody that you can there's a
school of thought Sudan some think it's
a my session guitar that says when you
feel upset at somebody you should
reflect that you put yourself here you
put them here obviously but you put them
in the room but you also put yourself in
the room so do it on two in two ways the
only person to blame is yourself you you
created them but you also put yourself
in the same room with people that you
don't like so
yeah that's called three spheres that's
fine
that's a that's really nice to think
about if you can and and don't feel lost
okay
don't feel like oh there's nothing there
there's nobody there actually as we're
going to learn today from the verse the
person you always felt was there was
never there
that's scary you see that's scary that
you spent all these years with will mean
who didn't exist you know protecting him
caring for him and so don't feel lost or
you know that the meditator is gone
somehow actually you just found the real
meditator for the first time so you
should feel some kind of comforting
greater consciousness yeah though
awareness of that Will's coming from
seeds arises from we've just studied it
last week millions of years of good
seeds to realize what's going on finally
comes from millions of years of good
seeds and the texts we were reading last
week was by whom first pension Lama
devil debates an angel and he said the
only way you could have made enough
karma to hear this teaching this week
was that you served a teacher and you
help the teacher spread the teaching and
so that's why we during the meditation
we focus on a teacher instead of a pizza
or watermelon okay cuz it's it's it's
automatic good karma to think about your
teacher and and according to the pension
law my first pension Lama that's the
only way to get enough karma to hear
someone teach the diamond cutter Sutra
one more question
Thank You team Thank You Kushina my
question is when you teach level a DCI
level seven you teach us for space and
now in this retreat you teach us lions
dance and this to meditation also
helpers supporters to see emptiness
directly so what's the connection
between these two and if we just have
one hour so you was supposed us to do
which meditation we should do if we have
two hours what we'll do the first and
what will be the next okay good thank
you the fourth kind of space in the four
spaces meditation is real emptiness
after playing with three kinds of things
that you might mistake for emptiness and
the emptiness of the Lama who's not
coming from you the boo-boo Lama is the
fourth kind of space so that's where the
two meditations connect
[Music]
we studied last week again in the first
pension Lamas text we learned well we
were trying to finish 25 wrong
meditations on emptiness he taught he
reviews 25 mistaken meditations on
emptiness and he spends some time
talking about doing the wrong kind of
meditation honest honest meditation
which is called naan kadavul naan
kadavul means space like meditation so
there are three classical mistakes about
what the space mean when you say space
like meditation which means meditation
and emptiness there were in history
three classical wrong ideas and when you
teach somebody meditation there's a
tradition to explain the wrong ones also
then they won't do it you see I mean
then they won't make that mistake and
start trying to do that kind of
meditation you see you explain
he explains twenty-five wrong kinds of
emptiness meditation then he only gets
the one correct one okay we didn't get
to it number 26 so there are three wrong
ideas about what the space like
meditation means one is what anybody
lowest one blue sky like I should and
you hear people you can read books you
know people who didn't get training and
they'll say think about the blue sky
it'll make you happy you know and then
the second kind outer space you know
space means the infinite black place
where stuff is sitting in it a third one
third one much more difficult that the
place where the clock is sitting right I
take the clock out of the space
I put the clock back in the space
there's a space here place where I can
put the clock I can take the clock on
that space is a little bit better
because it's the absence of something
it's a negative thing but that's the
absence of something which really exists
and that's not emptiness emptiness means
the absence of something that couldn't
exist and I like to give the example of
a credit card I have a I like to take
people out to dinner
cuz I like to eat dinner and I say I'll
take you guys out to dinner and then I
go out there's a DCI emptiness teaching
you then I'll change my clothes
I'll put on my black pants because they
look nicer and I'll leave my credit card
in my blue pants then when I get to the
restaurant I we eat and then I say don't
worry Nick I'll pay for dinner and then
I reach in my pocket and I am like and
then I realized I left my credit card in
my other pants ok but that's not the end
of the story what's the end of the story
it was a Discover card this is a special
kind of lousy credit card in America for
people who can't get a credit card and
just when you touch it you pay interest
like thousand percent you know it not
doesn't work it's a stupid credit card
it's a credit card that's not a credit
card understand when you forget that
kind of credit card that that's
emptiness see because it doesn't work
anyway even if I brought it it doesn't
work ok that's emptiness ok third kind
of space is the absence of a union card
or master
that works okay that's not emptiness
emptiness means the thing you thought
was there doesn't work anyway it's not
real it's not a real credit card okay
it doesn't matter it was there or not
okay so that's the fourth kind of space
so my suggestion is the fourth space is
meditation is shorter you know and when
you're teaching people I think it's good
to start with that this kind of lion
stance minimum it took us an hour it
took 50 minutes and I think it's for
when people are stronger in their
meditation we didn't do three parts of
it yet there's three more parts they're
called to gal kittens in and we're gonna
do that slowly every time we meet
together we'll make the meditation more
detail there's three more parts that we
have to do okay
that's my suggestion first meditation
should teach people as a Martin well
breath doesn't yeah don't Len
okay giving and taking okay that's the
first one that should always be the
first one because that really helps
people is that meditation in direct
contradiction to the misperception of
the world
you gotta think about it because
selfishness is somehow linked to
misunderstanding emptiness okay you have
to think about that okay all right let's
go to the you guys need a break I think
peepee bring okay let's take a pee-pee
break then we'll come back and do what
do we have to do Maya good okay illusion
number
yeah we finished Cameron finished star
cataract and butter lamp now we go to
illusion okay take a break green drink
tomorrow
those two guys girls will be standing at
the door and you have to give them the
verse to get in the class I'm not
kidding
okay got it so your ticket tomorrow to
the class is this Sanskrit verse okay
you don't have to sing it because some
people singing is pretty bad okay okay
you guys on okay you have to come a
little bit early tomorrow so you cannot
get in the class unless you can say this
okay
then I'll teach use principal in the
monastery when you don't know the verse
you you go Tyler God
[Music]
then the teacher goes okay
it's called wah wah it has a name it's
Co you think all those monks are all
singing the same thing okay
serious pretty serious okay alright to
get so come a little or come five
minutes early tomorrow because they'll
be in line alright okay we were doing
the illusion part we said it's gonna
have nine parts
I was talking to Veronica I don't know
if we can get to the scripture so maybe
we do five , she knows I'm not sure yet
I'm not sure yet we'll see okay we'll
see how it goes okay first one
what's this third group third group
second group call yeah nice how you
taste the world what's the first group
called yeah what is your world like it's
like a star it's like a I problem and
it's like a lamp okay that's how your
world is like now we reach the second
group which has how many members one and
it's how do you taste your world okay
and there are nine parts so Vasa Pandu
master vos a Pandu master Camila Sheila
John Shepard RJ Tony Lama
they all like to say our taste of the
world how we experience things is
mistaken okay we don't understand where
things are coming from okay we don't
understand where things are coming from
okay
for example the green drink some people
say Oh delicious some people like me say
Oh terrible then both the people who say
it's good and bad they feel like the
taste is in the cup they don't realize
taste is coming from their mind okay
from seed which they planted last week
last month last life okay we don't know
okay so the first idea about the
illusion is that all the things we taste
in the world meaning experience in
Buddhism taste means experience all the
things we taste we are making a mistake
we don't understand where they're coming
from okay that's the first one that's
the most important meaning of illusion
if you want to improve the taste of the
green drink at Diamond Mountain don't
talk to the cook okay talk nicer to
other people talk more sweetly to other
people and then your green drink will
taste good after a while okay because
it's coming from you
all right second one $10 Amba said this
is especially applies to pleasure and
pain okay we think it's coming from the
object but it's not that's an illusion
it's always coming from us
good feelings things that make us happy
and things that make us unhappy both are
coming from us okay and we don't
understand that okay so what's the
difference between the first one and the
second one in the second one we are more
talking about pleasure and pain where
this pleasure come from where this pain
come from okay in the first one we're
just saying all the stuff you experience
is really coming from you but it doesn't
look like that third one katieb timber
target sorry point shot tell me do me he
likes the explanation of Maya by
especially that the lower middle way
school likes to talk about it okay so
the lower middle way school likes to
talk about magic trick magic trick and
if you've ever been to India in the
village if you ever lived in a village
in India there are these traveling
magicians
and they come into town and everybody
gets really happy they all because they
don't have TVs and at least they didn't
use to have TV and I've seen them
they're amazing they're great magicians
and they come and they do some magic for
about an hour and everybody comes out of
their house and they all stand in the
street and they watch the magician okay
and they will take
a small piece of stick like smaller than
that about that big and they will throw
it on the ground okay then they have a
mantra this is the old meaning of the
word mantra and they have a special kind
of powder and they go and they blow the
powder on the people and they say mantra
and then it's a weird something happens
to your eyes you know and you can see a
horse from this thing you know and
sometimes they will make a beautiful
pony and all the kids are like oh yeah
and sometimes they will make a wild
horse and everybody you know so this is
a famous example in the lower middle way
school okay and they talk about who sees
the horse and who doesn't see the horse
okay and who believes in the horse okay
and then they talk about someone who
came they came out of their house late
and they didn't get the mantra and they
didn't get the powder okay
so there's three possibilities the
people who came out of their house first
who got heard the mantra and they got
the powder in their eyes do they see a
horse do they believe the horse yeah
okay that's first example okay
does the magician see your horse yeah he
got the powder he got them under he sees
a horse but does he believe the horse no
okay and the third possibility the
person who came later they're like why
is everybody laughing or why is
everybody running I don't see anything
there's they don't see horse and of
course they don't believe it in okay so
how do these compare
- illusion okay how do these compare to
illusion most people in the world are
like the people who got the powder and
they got the mantra okay they think the
green Jing taste is coming from the
green drink okay
they see the taste and they believe it's
in the green drink okay then how about
the magician oh sorry
how about the person who comes later who
are they like they are like an aria
somebody told me I shouldn't say I'll
kiss you so I'll give you a star
okay that's great the aya they don't see
the illusion and they don't believe in
it they they see what's real okay
they see there's no taste she wants to
know why I changed Siri series asking me
what do you need - she calls me - okay
okay so are you a person seeing
emptiness directly they don't believe it
and they don't see it they don't think
it's coming from the drink okay now what
about the magician that's more difficult
yeah in Aria who came down out of the
direct perception emptiness then
intellectually they understand the taste
is not coming from the drink but they
still taste it okay it still tastes like
that they still feel like that but they
know there's wrong they know that's an
illusion okay they know they're crazy
okay it looks like the taste coming from
the green drink but they know it's a
wrong feeling they know their equipment
is broken okay they know there's a
scratch on their eye okay they don't
believe it so
that's coins I'm Tammy doing me and what
he wants to emphasize is that in number
three okay in number three the emphasis
is that on the wild horse and the pretty
horse
okay the emphasis is on number in number
three the emphasis is on the beautiful
horse the pony or the wild horse who is
dangerous okay all of our fears and all
of our hopes are false okay all of our
fears
and all of our hopes we are reacting to
the second husband okay there's nothing
there okay
anytime you have a big fear about the
future anytime you have a big hope about
the future it's all mistake okay doesn't
mean you shouldn't want a nice future it
doesn't mean that if you want a nice
future just plant it okay you don't need
to have a hope you just do it
okay and you don't have to have a fear
about someone you don't like just fix
them okay so a person who understands
the illusion can have a sane life happy
life no more crazy emotions okay they
know where things are coming from okay
got it
so number two sorry number three the
emphasis is on the pony and the Crazy
Horse
okay stop having hopes stop having
worries about the future okay you don't
have to hope just do it just plant it
don't think maybe I'll get rich next
year or maybe I'll find a partner or
maybe my partner will change next year
don't hope just do it just plant it okay
all right
[Music]
number D number four
that's from Geshe Michael that one's
free okay
it means I just wanted to remind you of
the meaning of illusion in Buddhism okay
we don't believe everything's like
illusion so you should do what you want
okay we don't believe done
we don't believe nothing matters because
everything's illusion that's not the
meaning of illusion the meaning of
illusion is a discrepancy between what
you see and what is real okay that's the
only meaning of illusion what you think
is there doesn't match what is really
there and that's the only meaning of
illusion in Buddhism okay it looks like
the lousy taste of the cringe ring is
coming from the cooks in the kitchen but
actually it's coming from me okay
I did so that that's the meaning of
illusion that so what should be your
reaction to that meaning of illusion
yeah I have to be a nice person okay
someone who understands emptiness
automatically the sign that they
understand emptiness is that they
understand they have to be nice to other
people no choice no choice it's making
my world okay a sign that someone
doesn't understand emptiness is mad
nothing's real just do what you want you
know everything's the void you know I
can eat as many your jobs as I want
again the sign that someone doesn't
understand emptiness if they think
illusion means nothing matters and I
don't have to be a good person the sign
that someone does understand emptiness
is that they know they don't have a
choice they have to be a good person
okay alright so that's number four is
understanding the basic meaning of the
illusion okay the way it looks
and the way it is don't match okay
I'd like to call it discrepancy okay
number five was what I told you four
number four okay number five is the
three people involved a magician
the first spectator and the spectator
who came later that's number five okay
number three is the pony and the
stallion okay
so III little bit I said number five too
early okay number five it's the three
different kinds of people
magician spectator and later spectator
Arya the indirect perception Arya after
direct perception and normal people okay
number five is that what's number three
magic pony magic horse all your hopes
all your fears
okay our illusion okay every worry you
ever had was unnecessary okay we were in
Ukraine last month and we were talking
about this and it means every person you
ever got angry on or every person who
ever upset you wasn't there okay and
that means that every war that was ever
fought was fought against an enemy who
wasn't even there not in a metaphorical
sense in a real sense there was no enemy
there okay the enemy you thought was
there was not there the husband who
yelled at you from his side was not
there in World War two hundred million
people thirty million in China died for
nothing
okay for nothing no purpose the enemy
wasn't there okay
it's crazy okay it's the tragedy of war
okay there's no enemy okay what number
we are
ABCDEF six yeah okay this is a cool one
of course they're all cool this is how
master chandrakirti wants to talk about
it and especially he's commenting on the
four hundred versus chatter shot ago who
wrote it
i Adela who was the student of Ngong
Java okay so the gardener had a student
named aryadeva
he wrote a book called four hundred
verses and master chandrakirti who's
like the greatest commentator on
emptiness ever he gives two nice
examples that I thought you would like
to know okay
one is and and he says this illusion is
all about empty hopes he focuses on
empty hopes you have hopes you are
chasing things in your life goals empty
goals in your life okay that's number
six what he has two examples okay number
one a dog comes up to you and they're
hoping for a piece of food or something
and you I like to you know you go like
this you take a rock and you go and then
they're like you know then you throw the
rocks and then they run out to the rock
and then they're like you know okay so
chanting care to uses that example for
us chasing illusions okay maybe I can
get
maybe the stock market will work next
year or maybe I should use real estate
okay
what gets you Michael say about stock
market open the newspaper to the stocks
get a pen stand over the newspaper drop
the pen whatever the pen hits buy that
stock
okay but first help another person start
their business then the stock will
succeed okay
understand it's not coming from this dog
it's coming from you okay so a person
who studies the stocks talks to the
experts
looks at the statistics chooses
carefully a stock they are a dog chasing
it wrong okay they are a dog chasing
around maybe at work maybe hoo-hoo-hoo
it doesn't matter okay the experts don't
matter if the experts knew which stock
to buy they would buy the stock and they
wouldn't tell you okay if they knew they
were just quietly - dark and make my
money they don't know nobody knows where
to start going tomorrow nobody in this
planet knows okay drop it help someone
else start their business then buy any
stock it was 16
okay you will make money okay don't
chase rocks don't chase rocks
can you show their picture for this
meditation it's a method we're on
meditation number 21 okay
the picture yeah it's a baby and the
mother is putting a so chandrakirti says
oh you want another example it's the the
baby who gets the mother sticks their
finger in the baby's mouth then they're
like oh it's like the rock no milk
okay got it
I asked Veronica is it really like that
she said well they don't really expect
milk but anyway chapter Quixote was
among he didn't know he's like sucking
on a finger to get some milk okay
after a while the baby's like this isn't
working
[Music]
okay so to buy the stock based on the
expert it's like sucking on a finger to
get some mother's milk okay those are
the two famous examples that was number
six okay number seven coin show Tambor
Dumais goes one step more he says by the
way the thing about the finger in the
baby's mouth okay he says don't trust
successes that you get if you don't
understand them don't trust successes
you already got if you don't understand
them be careful okay everybody gets a
some success because of their old karma
okay then they get successful like
people who make a famous song from their
old Karma and they become famous for a
while then they try to make a second
song second albums are always terrible
right because their Karma finished okay
they don't know why they were successful
okay if you want to be a successful
singer what do you have to do
specifically huh yeah be friendly yeah
congratulate the other singers promote
the other singers I have a lady she came
to me she said I want to be a famous
actress then I said okay then you have
to help other actors and she's like no
no no we compete you don't understand
when there's one role in the movie 400
people get in line in Hollywood or a
thousand people get in line and we have
to compete with each other I said we'll
just just try it okay just try it
she got an Academy Award nomination okay
she came here she studied here so she
helped other people she made a little
school to help young actors okay all
right so number seven is stop
misunderstanding where your successes
come from okay your past successes
everything good in your life so far came
from your seeds you helped somebody else
don't misunderstand your successes which
also applies to your appearance your
body you know your education your
country they all came from Joe who's Joe
your past life I like to call him Joe
okay it's not your okay who gave Geshe
Michael blue eyes Joe I didn't do
anything I was born like that I've seen
I mean it's past life okay so understand
where things come from then you won't be
disappointed
you won't be the dog with the rock okay
you can make your future successes okay
number
Hey I just wanted you to know that this
particular word in Buddhism tasting and
experience I wanted you to know the
history of this words in Tibetan Ron
Yonghwa Ron young it comes from a famous
reference called
Pootie Lee Jung Jin Yong kuchela Jang
Jin Yong licking honey off a razor blade
licking honey off a razor blade okay
it's a famous Buddhist expression okay
you know you think something like
especially let's say adultery let's say
you're attracted to someone else's wife
or husband and then you think oh I would
be happy you know I can take this wife
or husband from this other person and
and I will lick the honey but under the
honey there's razor blade okay and you
will hurt yourself you will cut yourself
that's the other meaning of this word in
Buddhism okay tasting that taste it
means be careful about the things you be
careful to not do bad things to get good
things okay cuz that's like a razor
blade under the honey okay
it's a terrible image right somebody
should make a movie number 9 I like to
teach number 9 from the Geshe
examinations so you study for 20 years
25 years you do a couple of pre gues
examinations and then you do your Gersh
examination and it takes about two three
weeks
all the debaters in the debate ground
have to question you separately in my
the background there's 1500 people then
they question you in groups because
sophomore Klaus junior class and but the
last question is always in the temple
main temple and the old gays who they
don't have to come to debate ground
anymore
because they're so smart some of them
keep coming they can't stop until they
die they keep coming but they're nothing
they're not supposed to come they sneak
in and the last day they give everybody
I get your hat ok even the kids the 7
year old baby monks they get it guess
you had doctor hats like this big you
can't see the kid and they give
everybody I guess you had they keep my
monastery keeps 1,500 guessing that's in
a box everybody gets a gassy huntin the
last day ok then they ask you the last
question and the last question is always
the same and they say does the pain in
this world war hunger death disease does
it will it ever have an end you know is
it possible and will ever have an end
you know and then the answer is always
the same and the answer is yes you go
yes you know like you never heard the
question before yeah and then they say
why then you say because truth is
stronger than illusion truth is stronger
than illusion illusion will always fail
in time illusion will always fail the
second husband will always be unmasked
you'll understand the second husband
sooner or later
after many lives of suffering okay you
will understand he was never there
because the truth of emptiness is
stronger than lie illusion okay so and
then everybody takes the after guilty
hat and they throw it like a frisbee and
there's 1500 - he has going like this in
the sky it's the most beautiful thing
all these guys and then then you're a
gasps hey then everyone has to try to
find their hat and it takes like an hour
so that's my knowledge mine okay so uh
last thing about the illusion is that it
will always collapse there will always
collapse okay sooner or later everyone
will become enlightened okay because the
illusion doesn't stand you can't stand
okay
against emptiness the illusion will fail
sooner or later will fail okay and
everybody will be happy
all right we have another oh we have
quite some time you need air
conditioning raise your head it's not
hot enough yet okay
all right can we put the the verse back
up what's the next one ABBA Shia okay
say of a Shia of a Shia I thought you
know it means down okay though the
sanskrit prefix means down downwards
okay
Shaya comes from a root called xi which
means to coagulate something wet becomes
like if you blow your nose in here for
for 20 minutes it's goofy then later it
gets hard
that's called XI okay
the Ruchi booger getting hard something
like that okay jell-o stuff like that
it's called XI so other Shia means that
do which forms on the grass okay in the
morning okay on the tip of the grass the
little water one drop of water is other
Shia it came down and formed on the
grass
okay it's called uber Shia I was talking
to Veronica the the one word in English
that comes from she is scholar because
they sit on their butt all day and they
coagulate school comes from now so those
of you who hated school you were correct
it means to sit for a long time it's
called she sit comes from that so Shia
comes from that of a Shia I'm a Shia
okay this one's pretty easy there's only
four meanings okay by the way let's do a
illusion impermanence check illusion
impermanence check the Stars which one
illusion or impermanence both learn how
about the eye problem
both because the last quality was it
slow budva
it's removable it's impermanent okay
camera remember the lamp how how in I
can understand how it's impermanent
right how is it like an illusion
yeah that's pretty good even though it's
it still functions even though it's
empty
I'll go for that one okay coming up my
man kuma illusion huh
it's that illusion or impermanent ba
okay but how is it impermanent last
gadget question last question okay got
it so far the Buddhist mixing
impermanence and illusion he's trying to
show they are connected we're gonna talk
about it more later okay okay
so master bosib a new common uh Sheila
jong-il Shiva
Tony la Mer they say everything in your
life is like the dew on the grass okay
when the Sun comes out it never lasts
okay the dew on the grass never lost
so the first meaning for master Carmela
Sheila for vasa bandura it's just simple
impermanence okay do cannot last
especially at Diamond Mountain $10 on
bow who seems to be a little bit
pessimistic
he says especially the good things in
your life okay
so that's number two for him
the do especially represents the good
things in your life it's hard enough
life is hard good things don't happen
very often and when they happen they
disappear quickly normally if you're if
you understand the pen you can reinvest
and you can keep it going
for how long indefinitely
that's a Buddha paradise okay if you
understand that the good things in your
life are coming from your sins you can
just keep planting the seeds okay and
that would be a Buddha paradise know em
alright number three $10 Amma says by
the way that do doesn't just represent
impermanence it represents that those
good things in our life are unstable
they can flip in a few minutes okay
they're not just impermanent they can
become suffering in five minutes okay
a beautiful relationship can turn to a
lifelong hatred in a few days it's when
you call it it's unstable
okay things that come from seeds are
unstable now this part I I'm gonna spend
some time on the fourth one okay and for
me when I first read and I was talking
to Veronica about it when I first read
the diamond cutter Sutra and I got to
the end and I read this verse which is
so famous I felt disturbed by it I said
I don't understand he's trying to teach
impermanence or he's trying to teach
illusion because it's not clear you know
like candle looks like to me impermanent
illusion or dream
those are he must be talking about
emptiness right so I I used to be very
confused by this verse some things are
obviously impermanence like the dew on
the grass and then some things are
obviously
emptiness like illusion or dream okay
then it disturbed me that he's and I
asked many Lamas and I didn't get a good
answer
you know I was a little bit like nobody
gave me a good answer which made me
think nobody worried about it before and
then Master Dharma character gives a
good answer okay
Dharma cutie okay logician famous
Buddhist audition Adams translating his
stuff for the next ten years he you will
know he's finished with this book when
he gets a bald spot alright and master
Dharma Quixote in his most famous book
which is called Pomona Baraka which
means an explanation of correct
perception in explanation of correct
perception most famous Buddhist book on
logic source of all Buddhist logic
Pomona Vertica okay in there he has a
verse about it okay because it's
confusing by the way in the Sutra in the
other sutra where the Buddha teaches
this verse okay which is called the
cachaca Sutra and I don't know if
anybody noticed it but I did just before
he gives the verse he says let me tell
you something about emptiness and then
he says thorocotomy nam deep oh my he
goes like that
okay so in that Sutra Buddha seems to
think he's talking about emptiness
because he says let me tell you
something about emptiness and then he
says the verse okay so to me that means
Buddha thought he was talking about
empty
okay and by the way there's a secret
version of this verse in the Kalachakra
Tantra and it's from the it says from
the diamond color sutra in the
Kalachakra Tantra and there's 12
metaphors so if you pay extra I'll give
them to you later okay
just kidding I'll give them to you later
okay the Kalachakra Tantra quotes the
diamond cutter Sutra this verse and
gives twelve twelve different metaphors
okay on the other hand as I mentioned
it's a custom in Buddhist monasteries
for thousands of years before the
teacher teaches they're supposed to say
camera be given a given super to demean
or not intended did you see them did a
talk like that what's that mean it means
this teaching is impermanent the
students are all gonna die the teachers
gonna die the temple will fall down you
know then in ancient tradition this
verse a teacher supposed to say it
before they start the teaching so they
don't get a big head so they don't get
proud okay they're supposed to say come
around America thorocotomy tombliboo
then I'm gonna die tonight tomorrow we
don't know don't think you're a big Lama
you know tomorrow they may be dressing
you in the big Lamas clothes before they
burn you they're supposed to think like
that
okay so traditionally this verse has
been used for both purposes emptiness
because Buddha introduced it that way
but in the monasteries for thousands of
years people use it for impermanence so
my question is there a connection and
Dharma currently said yes
okay I found it took me a long time okay
some llama one of the tutors of the
eights dynamo he found it okay here we
go
[Music]
daegeum
me table dunya dunya Lainey dummy some
very famous line from Dharma cutie okay
and he says suffering comes from
impermanence and emptiness comes from
suffering so they're all connected okay
that's Dharma cutie I'll say it again
suffering comes from impermanence and
self because an emptiness comes from
suffering okay emptiness comes from
suffering so Dharma charity says the
three are connected deeply okay the
three are then he says at the end he
says soon what soon mean Buddha said so
okay Buddha said so then I went looking
okay in John Brady's database which has
every Buddhist scripture from India in
it I went looking
Buddha didn't said then I'm like come on
what it didn't say that then I was
sleeping and I I was like Oh duh he did
say that Buddha taught the four truths
right each truth has four parts okay
there are sixteen parts to the four
truth okay very very famous okay
each truth has four parts okay there are
sixteen aspects of the four our interest
okay each one has four parts what's the
truth suffering okay truth of suffering
and the four parts are metal dunya tomba
dog may impermanence suffering and
emptiness
okay buddha said that that's trade
there's two kinds of emptiness okay
emptiness of things the emptiness of
people okay these are the four parts of
the truth of suffering impermanence
suffering and two kinds of emptiness who
said there's a connection Buddha when
we're shopping sign our first teaching
okay
they went there she and candy went there
it's the first teaching he ever gave he
said things are impermanent things are
suffering and there's two kinds of
emptiness and they're all connected okay
we're in the first truth in the first
teaching he ever gave in the first
sentence he ever talked okay got it
okay and I like the summary of this
teaching that was given by th Oakland
young tonisha Johnson born 1713 died
1793 he was the teacher of the eighth
dalai lama jump el gato born 1758 died
1804 okay ready anybody know you guys
know what's he famous for young same
year she canton yeah i i'm not supposed
to say that i will pat you on the back
yeah he's very famous he wrote 2,000
pages of history of the llama in lamas
every lama of the long room starting
with buddha he wrote their life story
very beautiful very correct so if you're
a teacher and you want to know
if you're teaching about like the story
of the dog and Maitreya it's in the best
ones in there okay you just go to that
book parts of it have been translated
okay here's how he explained Dharma QT
got it who made our Goomba say if you
want to meditate on the middle way if
you want to meditate meditate on the
middle way date your meat are laid in
your dunya Lainey dummy so you should
study Dharma QT okay
you should ask Adam okay
why because Dharma charity said things
are impermanent because they're
impermanent their suffering and because
they're suffering they are empty he said
who's he Buddha said da mccurdy says
Buddha sin' okay then what's that mean
okay Young's and Yoshi Johnson says I'm
gonna explain this this lines to you and
he does a beautiful job okay ready
Tomomi talk only if you really want to
understand the middle way you should
start with the long room you should come
to the lamrim retreats okay because you
will be meditating first on impermanence
then you will be able to stop the baby
gotcha the most baby gotcha there is
what's the most baby what's gotcha mean
the thing that emptiness is emptier okay
that boo-boo llama not the husband who's
not coming from you okay the Discover
credit card then the lowest kind of
emptiness is to understand that nothing
lasts okay
relationships positions bodies countries
they don't last the lowest kind of
ignorance is to believe things are gonna
last for a while okay everyone who's
country was ever attacked they always
thought it was gonna be the next day
they weren't quite ready Los Angeles
could be wiped out next month okay
the North Koreans are close that will be
the end of the United States that would
be the beginning of the end of the
United States in every country that ever
fell down which is all the countries
they always thought they're gonna last a
little longer
you know nobody thought Los Angeles will
disappear next month but it's possible
okay it can happen it's closed and
everybody who lost their country I
always thought their country was gonna
last a little bit longer okay
that's the lowest kind of ignorance oh
this will last a little I'm not gonna
die today gosh you know we still have
some classes I have to clean out my
retreat count I have to pack I already
paid for the plane ticket home I I'm not
gonna die today
okay everybody thinks that the absence
of that is the lowest kind of empty
there is no lasting thing if a country
can if America can finish next month
your body can finish in a in a in a day
that's not a big thing
okay got it so he says if you meditate
on impermanence okay then you can stop
the lowest kind of ignorance which is to
think that things are still gonna last
for a while okay
Daegu jeongmi after you get used to that
lowest kind of emptiness hard to bear ha
Tom Jaudon Joey uma telugu malavika then
you're ready to start on higher kinds of
emptiness okay like the husband who
didn't come from me okay you start with
the lowest kind of emptiness the world
is empty of things that are still gonna
last a wild guess mom okay then you you
get used to gotcha cancelling gotcha
geshe michael who's gonna last for a
while still doesn't exist you get used
to that emptiness that space no doesn't
exist then you can move to higher gotcha
what's the highest culture second
husband in the kitchen okay a husband
who's yelling at me
because he wants to because he's stupid
he's a husband okay alright okay
long-term oh now he doesn't stop there
okay he just connected impermanence to
suffering to emptiness he should be
finished but he says by the way you have
to go further
after you cancel the second husband
that's not the end of the Buddhist
okay if you want to wait millions of
years to become a Buddha you can stop
there with the husband okay but if you
really want to become a Buddha
knock-knock mom huh yeah you have to
study the secret teachings you have to
study the secret teachings okay love and
say Nong then go back to impermanence
okay of you of your body of your life
okay why you don't have time okay you
got to get this thing done now okay if
there's a path that will work in a few
years instead of a few million years
okay you should be doing that you should
be doing that okay secret teachings okay
now this is really cool okay ready I'm
gonna teach you some secret teachings
because you're here I'm not gonna
announce I'm teaching secret teachings
and then the lazy people will come okay
I'm gonna teach secret teaching to the
people who came for the Lamia okay and
I'm not gonna announce we're doing
secret teaching you ready cut the lights
no it's okay it's okay then they are
listening this free okay what's the
gotcha in the secret teachings yeah
something ordinary normal okay
it's a wife or a husband who's not the
Buddha okay in the lower teachings
normal teachings we are cancelling the
husband who didn't come from me okay in
the the gotcha
in the lower teachings normal teachings
is the husband who didn't come from me
that's the gotcha but when you if you
want to become a Buddha in one lifetime
you got to move up to a higher garter
okay it's like moving from the gotcha of
will last for a while to the doctor who
didn't come from me got it
lower gotcha lowest gotcha a country
which will still last for well a life
which was still last for a while it
doesn't exist
cancel it do something now okay
that's the lowest gotcha what's the
middle gotcha
yeah a husband who's not coming from me
and then that's a higher emptiness
cancel that husband that's a higher
emptiness okay now you want to go the
highest emptiness what's the third
gotcha highest gotcha a husband who is
not already a Buddha
who is not already a buna okay in that
secret if you want to get enlightened in
one lifetime you have to go to that
emptiness who's not there in the kitchen
in the highest one who's not in the
kitchen yeah a husband who is not
already a Buddha geshe-la my husband's
not a buna he yells at me okay and for
that you need you need
why don't we meditate on the lamas bad
quality in the lion's den it doesn't
help you okay don't smell fart twice if
you're sitting next to Tim and he had
some bad food yesterday and you smell
something he make a boo boo Boop then
you don't go like is that you Tim don't
do that there's no benefit okay just
kind of get your air from the other side
so it's a principle in meditation that
you should meditate on something sweet
something beautiful okay somebody's good
quality don't waste your time in
meditation thinking about Tim's fart
yesterday okay it's not gonna make your
Buddha
okay don't waste your time I mean just
an example okay everybody fired thinking
so it's it doesn't help you okay now is
your husband really Buddha to be honest
you can't prove it and you can't prove
it's not true to be honest let's be
honest unless you can read its mind
unless you can see past and future lives
you don't know let's be honest okay if
you're a normal person we don't know you
know yeah maybe his husband maybe sorry
maybe he's Buddha maybe he's not gay I
don't know okay is it possible if he's a
Buddha that sometimes he will say bad
word to you yeah possible I mean I'm not
saying it's a proof okay possible he's
just normal stupid guy it's possible
okay
and normal stupid guy will say stupid
things okay we can accept that but if
he's a Buddha is it possible sometimes
he will say bad things to him yeah what
if he does if he's a Buddha and if he
says bad things to you why is he doing
it
he's forcing you to think about Kong
Ching he wants you to understand
emptiness okay I mean it's possible
possible he's just stupid guy okay
each is possible okay now using the
lions dance example okay a good teacher
is it more useful to believe is it more
useful to think probably his Buddha or
is it more useful to think probably his
stupid guy
which is better for you yeah okay okay
that's Tantra okay you want Tantra you
didn't even have initiation maybe that's
that's Tantra okay why are we talking
about that because this writer says move
up to a higher gotcha okay he says not
only is impermanence connected to
suffering connected to emptiness but
there are connected to higher doctor
okay the husband who's not a Buddha okay
so what's the higher emptiness that's
the higher dependent origination
what's the higher emptiness there's no
husband in my kitchen who's definitely
not a Buddha okay
that's the highest emptiness okay got it
is it true is it true that there's no
husband in your kitchen who is
definitely not a Buddha yeah it's true
unless you can read his mind you know
and the Buddha's not showing you a
different mind okay got it
so that's very beautiful he says that
that solved the problem of the last
verse of the jinkin Ching is it about
emptiness or is it about impermanence
they say yes bah bah every every 9 thing
is about bow emptiness and impermanence
why Buddha teach two different things -
la that's the first thing he ever taught
in his life was the first thing he ever
said when he got enlightened he said
four parts to the first truth me thought
Daniel Tom but dummy impermanent
suffering and two kinds of emptiness
okay it's the first thing he ever
thought get used to it you know it's
it's not so weird that he mentioned it
in that diamond color Sutra okay you
don't know it's the first thing Buddha
ever taught
I can't got it and then if you're gonna
follow this Lama this famous Lama you
have to go higher impermanent suffering
empty and not not Buddha
not not muna okay
highest gotcha highest kind of emptiness
got it cool now I can't think anything
else to teach you
I say let's stop there
there's also oh okay one more I'll give
you a dessert okay Buddha also taught
that idea in the glorious image of
Tantra okay what we just talked about
everything is in the gorgeous image of
Tantra okay
and it's in another book okay ready
that's the last thing okay hmm
I know I have 15 minutes but I'm just
being dramatic Santana
antara CD Santana antara CD who said
that I will pat you on the back
Santana means mindstream
it also means good music antara means
other person other person city means
proof so many people ask me gorilla if
things are coming out of my seats then
I'm very lonely person
why because I'm the only person in the
world why I'm making all the other
people it's so lonely you know they're
all in my head guess you know I'm just
living in my head and there's no other
people because you told me llamas coming
from my seats then it's lonely in here
you know everybody around me coming from
my seats you know I must be the only
person in the world then that's a super
lonely okay somebody asked Dharma
Keerthi okay same llama say llama
somebody asked Dharma Quixote am I alone
you know it's the whole world you know
coming from me am I alone then some of
my students in Beijing asked me this
question and dr. Wu asked me this
question then a we had a jinn saying
pizza party dr. Wu got some really good
ginseng we put it on a pizza and we had
an all-night teaching and it was really
fun you should try it
we should make a ginseng pizza stores in
the US so anyway we read this scripture
and the answer is yes you are making
people but there are other people you
are making them as outside people
therefore they are not you and they are
separate from you are they coming from
you yes are they coming from you as
people in your head no are they coming
from us people who are outside of you
yes are they coming from us people who
are outside of you who are not connected
to you necessarily yes can you fight
with those people can you get married to
those people yes
are you marrying yourself no I can't got
it that's his answer now in that book he
quotes himself okay JJ Daniel a girl
named Danielle come by somebody and
Yankee Dan can they can't anytime at
Titanian tony tommy bahama de chimie
today dunya to me on any dimension the
last 10 lines are the same as his more
famous book which is called yeah study
of accurate perception okay he quotes it
again
he says the buddha said things are
impermanent
therefore they are and therefore they
are then he explains the verse again in
this book okay ready
you neck you can't get any of this
without john brainy and nick you should
give them
[Applause]
DJ daniela Ghani Suns Curtis are
suffering okay
things that were put together by causes
and the causes that put them together
are suffering do y'all go about somebody
you should meditate on this suffering
naked and then can like a Yankee day on
can make a they need that with that in
my own suffering has come from the same
causes and you can also read it as my
own Buddhahood came from the same causes
okay Buddha Dana Dartmouth d'Artagnan
you want to know what's the foundation
for seeing emptiness understand
impermanence and suffering okay
don't need Darwin to a girl the the
understanding of emptiness which is
based on an understanding that nothing
lasts will free you from the Wheel of
Life
okay got it gamba sama dead onion there
is no form of meditation in Buddhism
which is not connected to this okay
there is no form of meditation in
Buddhism which is not founded on view of
emptiness based on suffering based on
impermanence any other meditation is not
Buddhist who said that Buddha okay de
chimie Tali Daniel Daniel any dimension
that's why I taught that suffering is
based on impermanence and emptiness is
based on suffering okay
last comment then I'll let you go
start by the way there what do we teach
people at the SCM teacher training
there's three skills to being a great
teacher number one know your subject
perfectly number two
get familiar with the students know
their past what they need number three
let them out early sometimes okay
danyoung keeping out some not gonna let
Danielle gone but some company my aunty
this is Dharma charity he says when
Buddha taught that you should meditate
on suffering as the foundation of seeing
emptiness okay he wasn't just talking
about dunya dunya suffering of suffering
how many kinds of suffering on there
three first one suffering and suffering
classical example headache or backing
second kind of suffering guilt away
Daniel suffering and change classic
example a good meal at a good restaurant
okay third kind of suffering Cappadocia
dunya we can say the human condition the
human condition everyone has to get on
everyone has to die people you like
people you don't like famous people
anonymous people powerful people little
people sick people healthy people young
people old people all the same okay they
all have the third kind of suffering
they will die and they will get on so no
no reason to hate other people we are
all in the same bad Titanic all right
their chart numb date some keep their
jacket didn't bark your nacho so someone
on tarragon 18 again
young dumb dumber he says that maturity
says the reason the Buddha taught
emptiness based on suffering based on
impermanence is he didn't want people to
think the only kind of pain is the pain
that hurts right now okay he didn't want
people to fall into the trap of thinking
that the nice things in your life are
not pink okay
and we kicked butt on what were we on
yeah the do we finish to do but in
finishing the shortest most obvious one
okay we also finished work
we finished the mystery of the verse why
is he mixing up examples for
impermanence with examples for emptiness
okay is he confused you know it's Buddha
confused he can't get his his metaphor
straight okay so just to review we used
the simplest one to do as an excuse to
go answer that question mainly from
Dharma kitty okay
mainly from Democratic okay so you can
appreciate now why these things come
together things that are obviously
illusions like dream or illusion what's
the dream here swapna okay we'll talk
about it tomorrow
hopefully okay and Maya okay
why is he mixing illusion metaphors with
of a Shia which is what they do on the
grass
why is he mixing them now you know why
okay you you're now an expert on the
connection between impermanence and
emptiness okay and by the way what
happened in the mean time from that
Teacher of the eighth day will happen
from the Teacher of the eighth time yeah
we connected it to the higher teachings
we connected it to the higher teaching
he said because those impermanence
meditation emptiness meditation
suffering meditation will kick you up
- the higher teachings okay where the
gotcha is a husband who's not a Buddha
the gotcha is a husband who's not a
Buddha okay one last question if you can
answer it you get to go home
six minutes Ernie how did he connect
that to the secret teachings do you
remember we were talking about
impermanence suffering and emptiness why
did the that Lama connected to the
secret teachings what was his segue what
was his bridge your clothes your clothes
yeah you don't have time you don't have
time okay here impermanence okay you if
you don't have time you should study
Vajrayana okay if you don't have time
you should go straight to bed your honor
okay so I'm sneaking Audrianna into the
alarm room because I want serious
students for Vajrayana
I don't want to announce we're doing
Vajrayana and a bunch of unserious
people who are too busy to come to just
mom room understand you're the hardcore
people who are smart enough to come to
mom men I mean most of you